Guide to the David Smith Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
David Smith Papers
1790-1859
GEN MSS 1399
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
5.63
14 boxes
The papers consist of a selection of David Smith's personal papers and a library of his autograph sermons dating from 1796 to 1859. The personal papers are autograph manuscripts including ten volumes of his journals, his school notes, speeches, and keys to the abbreviations he used in his writings. Also present is Smith's manuscript song book containing compositions on themes such as Bunker Hill and the death of General James Wolfe, an autograph sermon by Rev. Alexander Gillet (1749-1826), and an autograph "Articles of Faith" by Rev. Humphrey Mount Perrine (1785-1849). Smith's sermons comprise the bulk of the papers, and are arranged by numbers that he assigned, falling roughly in chronological order. Sermon themes, series, and titles are described at the folder level in the finding aid; topics include salvation, thanksgiving, singing, church discipline, sacraments, and the death of George Washington.
Smith, David, 1767-1862
Anderson, Alexander, 1775-1870
Gillet, Alexander, 1749-1826
Perrine, Humphrey Mount
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Personal Papers, 1790-1859. II. Sermons, 1796-1859.
David Smith (1767-1862, Yale 1795)
David Smith was born in Bozrah, New London County, Connecticut, on December 13, 1767, the son of Captain Ebenezer Smith, who had served in the American Revolution, and his wife Sarah. At age three he moved with his family to Berkshire, Massachusetts, and grew up on the family farm there. When Smith was 16 or 17 he married Betsy Marsh, and the couple had one son, David Marsh. His wife's death on August 11, 1789, inspired Smith to prepare for college, which he at first did independently and then with Rev. Jacob Catlin of New Marlborough, Massachusetts.
In 1792, Smith was accepted at Yale College as a sophomore and graduated three years later with the Class of 1795. Following college he taught school in Sheffield, Massachusetts, and in 1796 began study in theology with Rev. Ephraim Judson of Sheffield. Smith was licensed to preach by the Association of Berkshire County in October 1796. On February 10, 1799, he preached in Durham, Connecticut, and soon after was asked by the town to settle there as the second minister of Durham, succeeding Rev. Elizur Goodrich (1734-1797, Yale 1752). Smith married as his second wife Catharine Goodrich (1776-1845), the daughter of Rev. Goodrich.
In 1821 David Smith was elected one of the Fellows of Yale College, and held this position forty years until he tendered his resignation the close of the session in 1861; he was never absent from a regular meeting of the corporation. In 1830 he received an honorary Doctor of Divinity degree from Hamilton College. Smith retired from the ministry in 1833 and pursued farming. During his later years he preached occasionally in towns around Durham, and died March 5, 1862, at the home of his daughter Catherine Ellsworth in Fair Haven, Connecticut, at age 94.
Scope and Contents
The David Smith Papers consist of a selection of his personal papers and a library of his autograph sermons dating from 1796 to 1859. The personal papers in Series I are autograph manuscripts that include ten volumes of his journals, his school notes, speeches and addresses, and keys to the abbreviations he used in his writings. Also present is Smith's manuscript song book containing compositions on themes such as Bunker Hill and the death of General James Wolfe, an autograph sermon by Rev. Alexander Gillet (1749-1826), and an autograph "Articles of Faith" by Rev. Humphrey Mount Perrine (1785-1849).
Series II holds Smith's sermons, and they comprise the bulk of the papers. The manuscripts are arranged by consecutive numbers that Smith assigned, falling roughly in chronological order. Nearly all of the sermons follow the same structure and are divided into two sections. The first begins with a Bible verse as a headline; occasionally the verse is superseded by a more formal title. The section, which generally runs to ten pages, follows an interpretation of the verse. The second section (of about the same length) is introduced with a headline such as "Improvement," "Application," "Reflection," "Inferences," or "Remarks," and all sermons conclude with "Amen." Each sermon was annotated at the end with the date and place it was written, as well as where and when it was delivered; some of the sermons were delivered more than a dozen times over several decades. In addition to dates, some later sermons include a reference to Smith's own age. Many sermons also have notations on hymns or psalms on their first page or on the inside of the booklet's cover.
Theologically, David Smith was likely influenced by the Second Great Awakening. As is to be expected in a collection covering a lifetime of preaching, there is a wide variety of themes to be found in his sermons but some of those appearing with regularity are divine magnitude and providence, the frailty of human life, human iniquity and sin, divine law and judgment, and personal sanctification. Other categories include Thanksgiving, singing, church discipline, sacraments, and events in American history such as "the landing of our Fore-Fathers at Plymouth Dec. 22, 1620" (no. 773) and the death of George Washington (nos. 78 and 123).
Smith copied most of his sermons into small blank books bound with assorted of marbled, silvered, and tinted papers used as wrappers. Thirteen of the volumes bear rose-colored brocade-patterned "Dutch gilt" paper signed by Paul Reimund (or Reymund, 1763/4-1815) of Nürnberg, Germany; they are booklets beginning with sermons 547, 594, 652 (printed in brown), 663, 720 (single unlined sheet, not attached), 852, 862, 901, 931, 958, 1080, 1114, and 1842. Several binding techniques were employed, including a variety of turn-ins and a range of papers used as liners or stiffeners for the covers. In two cases the "endpapers" are repurposed illustrated ream wrappers from the paper mills of David Ames in Springfield, Massachusetts (no. 781) and William Coles in Middletown, Connecticut (no. 958). The latter features an Alexander Anderson wood engraving of a mill which was also used by Coles' contemporary, George Cox & Company of Hallowell, Maine, on a wrapper in 1826 (see John Bidwell, American Paper Mills, 1690–1832, 2013, page 160).
Clergy -- Connecticut; Clergy -- Connecticut -- Durham; Congregational churches -- Connecticut; Congregational churches -- Clergy; Congregational churches -- Sermons; Paper mills -- Pictorial works; Sermons, American; Songbooks, English -- Connecticut; Songs, English; Connecticut -- Religion -- 18th century; Connecticut -- Religion -- 19th century; Connecticut -- Religious life and customs; Durham (Conn.: Town) -- Religion -- 19th century; Diaries -- Connecticut -- 19th century; Ream wrappers -- Connecticut -- Middletown -- 19th century; Ream wrappers -- Massachusetts -- Springfield -- 19th century; Sermons -- Connecticut -- 18th century; Sermons -- Connecticut -- 19th century; Speeches (documents) -- Connecticut -- 19th century; Clergy -- Connecticut -- Durham -- 18th century; Clergy -- Connecticut -- Durham -- 19th century; Anderson, Alexander, 1775-1870; Gillet, Alexander, 1749-1826; Perrine, Humphrey Mount; Smith, David, 1767-1862; Washington, George, 1732-1799 -- Death and burial; Wolfe, James, 1727-1759; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1795
- Personal Papers, 1790–1859; Series I; 0.42; 1 box
  Scope and Contents
  The series holds a mix of personal and professional writings by Smith, including his journals, school notes, and speeches. Also present are two writings by other preachers working in Connecticut at the time, Alexander Gillet (1749-1826) of Torrington, and Humphrey Mount Perrine (1785-1849) of Cheshire.
  - Story, essay, and poems, 1790–1793 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Contents: "A Dialogue between a young married couple as they walked abroad in a fine summer day" ("composed after school hours at night," Canaan, 1790), "On the vanity of youth" (poem, 1792), "Reflections on the death of a most amiable companion" (essay, 1791), and two untitled poems (Yale College, 1793).
  - School notebook, with list of books, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Questions in Divinity Answered", 1794–1796 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Three autograph notebooks.
  - Music book, circa 1795 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Manuscript music book, containing songs, with music for one, two, or four verses, and separate texts. Song titles include "Death of General Wolf" and "Bunker-Hill."
  - Explanation of abbreviations characters used in the writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1820–1859 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Volumes 2-11 of Smith's autograph journals into which he made entries annually on his birthday, New Year's Day, and occasionally a day in mid-summer.
  - Address to Society of the Cincinnati, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "A charge", 1848 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Address written for the ordination of Rev. James R. Mershan, April 28, 1848.
  - "A Confession of Faith Covenant", undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Corner stone", undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Two autograph notebooks, one possibly the text of Smith's address delivered at the laying of the corner stone of the third meeting house in Durham, July 17, 1835.
  - "The importance of early cultivation improvement of the mind", undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Address given at an unidentified "Lyceum."
  - "A natural curiosity", circa 1791 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Autograph notes on a cave near South Marlborough, Massachusetts.
  - "Regeneration the work of God", undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Written for publication in the American Preacher.
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1793–1810 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sermon by Alexander Gillet, 1809 September 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Autograph sermon by Rev. Alexander Gillet of Torrington, Connecticut; annotated by Smith: "This is a sermon of Rev. Mr. Gillet father of Rev. Timothy Gillet of Branford. -- A Curiosity."
  - "Articles of Faith" by Humphrey Mount Perrine, 1815 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Autograph articles signed and dated by Rev. Perrine in Cheshire, Connecticut.
  - Sermon in unidentified hand, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    "Lamentations 1. 6. written over in part 1834"
- Sermons, 1796-1859; Series II; 5.21; 13 boxes
  The first subseries, Numbered Sermons, holds texts numbered from 1 to 1179. Generally, and with only few exceptions, the enumeration follows a chronological order determined by the date of composition. Sermons numbered 1-513 are organized chronologically, and were bound singly or in pairs. These pairs seem to have been conceived as one longer sermon, the first part to be preached in the morning, the second in the afternoon; however, they do have separate numbers. Sermons numbered 513-1179 were copied into booklets with four to eight sermons in each. These booklets often have a theme, and while the chronological order is kept within the booklets, it varies overall due to this thematical ordering. Many booklets do not have a title and their nature is still to be determined. Recurring categories are: "Sacramental," "Funeral Discourses," Thanksgiving sermons, Fasting sermons, and New Year sermons.
  The second subseries holds a collection of sermons bound together as "Discourses on Salvation." The third subseries, Other Writings, contains unnumbered sermons (also in booklets), special sermons which do not follow the general sermon structure, as well as notes and fragments. Some booklets have further notations on the cover, the most frequent being "B" or "Bene."
  David Smith preached most sermons more than once, generally three to five times, but some were delivered up to twenty times. The dates and places of each ministry are noted at the end of each sermon. Many sermons were used even decades after they were written, and some (see Box 12, folder 89, as an example) were preached earlier than they were copied into a booklet.
  When specific titles or themes are present on the sermons they are mentioned below. {Brackets around numbers} indicate a group of sermons that are bound together in one booklet. A key to the abbreviations and symbols that Smith used throughoutin his writings is in Series I, Box 1, folder 5.
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries: Numbered Sermons, Discourses on Salvation, and Other Sermons.
  - Numbered Sermons
    Smith numbered his sermons consistently from 1796 through 1825. Some numbers were assigned twice but the texts are different, and approximately thirty sermons were not numbered at all. Many sermons are missing from the collection; some were intentionally excised from their booklets.
    - Nos. 1-2, 8-9, 15-17, 1796–1797 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      2: includes note: "These were the first sermons I ever preached." 1-2, 8-9, and 16-17 are paired sermons.
    - Nos. 25, 27, 30, 35, 42-43, 1797–1798 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      42-43 are paired sermons.
    - Nos. 46-47, 78, 84, 1798–1800 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      46-47 are paired sermons. 78: "A sermon on the death of General Washington."
    - Nos. 101-108, 1800 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      101-108 are a series titled "The truth of scripture vindicated."
    - Nos. 111, 113, 116, 121, 123, 126 (2), 130-131, 1800–1801 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      123: "Sacramental"; 126: On the turn of the century, titled "A Century Sermon" (preached on January 1, 1801) contains a reference to George Washington; 130-131 are paired sermons titled: "Prayer a duty, important & beneficient."
    - Nos. {140-141}, 146, 153-154, {173-174}, {175-176}, {177-178}, 183, {191-192}, {195-196}, {199-200}, 1801–1802 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      140-141: "A Sermon for Fast"; 146: "Sacramental"; 153: "Sinners Threatened"; 154: "Christ the end of the Law"; 173-174: "The wickedness of confounding good & evil"; 175-178: [series] numbered "Discourse" 1-4; 183: "Sacramental"; 191-192: "Fast Sermon."
    - Nos. {201-202}, 213, 221, {223-224}, {225-226}, 227, 243, {253-254}, 255, 269, {270-271}, 278, {284-285}, 288, {289-290}, {292-293}, 297, 1802–1805 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      213: "A Thanksgiving Sermon"; 221: "Funeral Discourse"; 225-226: "A Fast Sermon"; 227: "For Contribution"; 243: "Sacramental"; 253-254: "A Fast Sermon"; 255: "A Sermon preparatory to Ordination"; 270-271: "The critical state of God's chosen people"; 284-285: "The Last Times"; 288: "Sacramental"; 289-290: "Sacramental"; 297: "For Contribution."
    - Nos. {325-326}, {348-349}, 351, 358, 366, 369, {373-374}, 378, 382, {385-386}, 387-388, 394, 396, 396, 1806–1807 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      358: "Sacramental"; 366: "Sacramental"; 369: "A Thanksgiving Discourse"; 388: "On Church discipline"; no. 396 used twice but different texts, first "Communion" and second "On singing."
    - Nos. 400, {401-402}, 403, {411-412}, 414, {421-422}, 431-432, 436, 439, {443-444}, 445, 1807–1809 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      400: "Sacramental"; 403: "Sacramental"; 414: "Family Government"; 421-422: "Fast Sermon"; 431: "Sacramental"; 445: "Sacramental."
    - Nos. {446-447, 451-455}, {448-449}, 450, 456, {457-458}, 463, 466, 471, 473, 483, 495-498, 1809–1810 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      448-449: "A Fast Sermon"; 450: "A Funeral Sermon"; 457-458: "Harvest"; 466: "Sacramental"; 471: "Funeral Sermon"; 483: "Sacramental"; 497: "A Thanksgiving Sermon."
    - Nos. 500, 509-510, {511-512}, 513, {516-518, 525-526}, 519, 1810–1811 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      511: "A Discourse to youth"; 513: "A Funeral Discourse"; 519: "Exposition."
    - Nos. {520-523, 533, 537}, 527, {528-529}, {531-532, 538, 540, 544-545}, 536, 1811–1813 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      527: "A Thanksgiving Discourse"; 536: "A Funeral Sermon."
    - Nos. {524, 539, 578, 590, 655}, 1811–1816 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      "Sacramental Discourses."
    - Nos. {542-543}, {547-548, 553, 556}, 549-550, 557, 1812 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      542-543: "A Fast Sermon"; 549: "A Fast Sermon Extraordinary"; 550: "A Missionary Sermon"; 557: "A Thanksgiving Sermon."
    - Nos. {559-560, 563-565}, 562, {566, 571-572}, {569-570}, 1813 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      562: "Sacramental"; 566-572: "Funeral Sermons"; 569-570: "A Fast Sermon."
    - Nos. 573, {573-574, 576, 580, 583-584, 589, 592}, 579, 1813–1814 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      573: "A Missionary Sermon"; 584 and 592: Sermons on God's judgment; 579: "A Fast Sermon - A spiral National Fast."
    - Nos. {582, 600-601, 603}, 585, {586, 591, 593, 612, 614}, {587-588}, 1813–1814 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      582-603: Sermons on Sanctification; 585: "A Thanksgiving Sermon"; 586-614: "Funeral"; 587-588: "Sermons on Intemperance."
    - Nos. {594, [604] 606}, {596-597, 599, 617}, 1814 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      604: only first page, the rest having been cut out of booklet.
    - Nos. {595, 613, 618, 634, 641}, 1814–1815 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Nos. {607-609, 619-623}, 611, 616, 1814 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      611:" A Sermon to the Gent Society in Durham"; 616: "A Thanksgiving Sermon."
    - Nos. {624, 641, 646, 646}, {627-628, 643-644, 650-651}, 1815–1816 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Nos. {630-631}, {633, 635-636, 639, 642, 648}, {645, 673, 675, 682}, 1815 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      630: "A Fast Sermon"; 636: "The worth of the soul"; 645-682: "Funeral Occasions."
    - Nos. 647, {652, 662-[664]}, {653-654, 656-657, 674}, 1815–1816 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      647: "A Thanksgiving Sermon"; 664 only first page, the rest cut out; 653-674: "On the Trinity."
    - Nos. 658, 660-661, {663, 669-670, 683}, 1816–1817 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      658: "A Discourse to Children"; 660-661: "A Fast Sermon"; 663-683: "Sacramental."
    - Nos. {665-668}, 1816 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Nos. {671, 677, 681, 685, 687}, 1816–1817 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      Sermons on "Resurrection."
    - Nos. {672, 680, 684, 689, 691-693, 697}, 676, 1816–1817 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      676: "A Thanksgiving Sermon."
    - Nos. {678, [no number]}, {679, 730, 753}, 1817-1820, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      678: "A Sermon on Singing"; unnumbered sermon dates from 1852 with title "A Sermon for New Year"; 679-753: "New Year. Discourses"; second booklet includes an autograph hymn.
    - Nos. 688, {690-691, 699-700}, {690, 696, 735}, 1817–1819 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      688: "A sermon preached at Wallingford at the formation of an auxiliary Bible Society"; 690-735: "Sacramental."
    - Nos. {694-695, 703, 705, 707}, 698, 1817 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      698: unfinished sermon, never preached, with title "A Funeral Sermon."
    - Nos. {709, 711, 713, 721}, {710, 715, 723, 725-726}, 1818 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Nos. {714, 741, 793, 810}, 1818–1822 (Box 6, Folder 49)
      "Funeral Sermons"; 714: revision of no. 415.
    - Nos. {716-717, 728-729, 731, 733-734}, 720, 724, 1818–1819 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Nos. 727, 739-740, {742, 744-747}, 1818–1819 (Box 6, Folder 51)
      739-740: "A Fast Sermon."
    - Nos. {743, 748-749, 752}, {745, 758, 778-779, 786, 797}, 1819–1822 (Box 6, Folder 52)
      745-797: "Sacramental Discourses."
    - Nos. 751, {757, 759-760}, 760-761, 1819–1822 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      751: "A Thanksgiving Sermon"; 760-761: "A Fast Sermon."
    - Nos. {762-766}, {767, 769-770}, 1820 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Nos. {772, 775-777, 780}, 773, {781-782, 784-785, 787-788}, 1820–1821 (Box 7, Folder 55)
      773: "A Sermon on the landing of our Fore-Fathers at Plymouth Dec. 22, 1620. Preached at Durham Dec 31, 1820. The sickness of my family prevented my writing or preaching this sermon on the 22nd as was intended."
    - Nos. 783, {789-791, 794-796}, {799-803}, 1821–1822 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      796: "A better country."
    - Nos. {798, 827, 860}, 1822–1824 (Box 7, Folder 57)
      "Discourses for the New Year."
    - Nos. {806, 813, 818, 831, 841, 849}, {807, 809-811, 814}, 1822–1823 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      806-849: "Sacramental."
    - Nos. {815-817, 820, 837-838}, 821, 835-836, 1822–1823 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      820: "This is a subject of great importance both as it respects the temporal & spiritual interests of mankind"; 821: "A Thanksgiving Sermon"; 835-836: "Discourses for Fast."
    - Nos. {833, 848, 850, 855, 940, 9[4]7, 1053}, 1823–1830 (Box 8, Folder 60)
      "Funeral Occasions."
    - Nos. {839, 853, 856, 858}, {840, 842, 844-847}, 1823 (Box 8, Folder 61)
      839: "On murder and the guiltiness of mankind through having crucified the Christ."
    - Nos. {852, 869, 880, 885}, 857, {861, 946, 1024-1025}, 1823–1829 (Box 8, Folder 62)
      857: "A Thanksgiving Discourse"; 1024: "Sacramental."
    - Nos. {862-864, 873-874}, {875, 878-879, 881-883, 1824 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Nos. {876-877, 975, 997}, 878, {884, 886-888, 918, 920-921}, 1824–1829 (Box 8, Folder 64)
      878: "On American Independence"; 884-921 "Gr. Salvation - Christ's enemies."
    - Nos. 889, {889-890, 899-900}, {894-898}, 1824–1825 (Box 8, Folder 65)
      889: "A Thanksgiving Sermon"; booklet 894-898: pages 1-42 missing; 894: On prejudice.
    - Nos. {901, 908, 912, 916}, {902, 906-907, 909-911}, 903-904, 1825 (Box 9, Folder 66)
      901: "Sacramental"; 903-904: "A Fast Sermon."
    - Nos. {905, 965, 1154-1155}, 1825–1845 (Box 9, Folder 67)
      Includes a preface, probably for 905, titled "To promote Missionary Contributions."
    - Nos. {912-915, 919, 922-923}, {924-926, 929-930, 936}, 1825–1826 (Box 9, Folder 68)
      929-930: "On Family Prayer."
    - Nos. {917, 952, 1038}, 1825–1830 (Box 9, Folder 69)
      New Year Sermons for 1825, 1827, and 1830.
    - Nos. 927-928, {931, 937-939, 951}, {935,937}, 1826–1827 (Box 9, Folder 70)
      927-928: "A Fast Sermon"; 931-951 "Christ's Intercession"; 931: "Sacramental"; 935-937: 66 pages cut out.
    - Nos. {938, 941-942}, {948-950, 953-954, 961}, 1826–1827 (Box 9, Folder 71)
      948-949: "On Human Depravity"; 950: "Last Day of the Year."
    - Nos. {955-957, 959-960}, {962-963}, {964, 970, 978, 980-981}, 1827 (Box 9, Folder 72)
      964: "The Sting of Death"; 964-981: "Sting of death is sin."
    - Sacramental - Nos. {958, 978, 998, 1004, 1018}, 1827–1829 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - Nos. {966-969}, {971, 973-974, 977}, 979, 1827 (Box 10, Folder 74)
      971-977: Booklet has inscription "Divine Love" on the back; 973: On John 8:36 - Freedom in Christ; 979: "Thanksgiving Sermon."
    - Nos. {982-986}, {987-989, 992-993}, 1828 (Box 10, Folder 75)
      983-984: "Duties of a Minister & People."
    - Nos. 990-991, {994-996, 999-1000}, {1003}, 1828 (Box 10, Folder 76)
      990-991: "Fast Sermon"; 1003: pages 1-42 missing.
    - Nos. 1005, {1006-1008, 1010}, {1011-1014}, 1828–1829 (Box 10, Folder 77)
      1005: "A Thanksgiving Sermon"; 1006: "Reconciliation to God"; 1009 apparently cut out; 1010: "The extent of the Divine curse."
    - Nos. {1015-1017, 1020}, {1021-1023, 1026}, 1829 (Box 10, Folder 78)
      1015: "The unpardonable sin explained"; 1023: "The Sabbath."
    - Nos. {1023, 1027-1029}, {1030-1033}, 1829 (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - Nos. {1034, 1039, 1050}, 1035, {1036-1037, 1040, 1045}, 1829–1830 (Box 10, Folder 80)
      1040: "The doctrine of submission."
    - Nos. {1041-1044}, {1046, 1060-1062}, 1830 (Box 11, Folder 81)
      1043: "The Sabbath"; 1044: "Christ is God"; 1060-1061: "The Last Times."
    - Nos. {1047-1049, 1059}, {1051-1052, 1054}, 1055-1056, 1830 (Box 11, Folder 82)
      1059: "On Church Disciple"; 1055-1056: "Fast Sermons."
    - Nos. {1057, 1073, 1081, 1086}, {1058}, {1063-1066, 1086}, 1830–1831 (Box 11, Folder 83)
      1057-1086: "Sacramental Discourses"; 1066: "Universal Providence."
    - Nos. {1067, 1071}, 1068, {1069-1070}, 1830 (Box 11, Folder 84)
      1068: "A Thanksgiving Sermon."
    - Nos. {1072, 1075-1076}, {1078-1080}, 1080, 1830–1831 (Box 11, Folder 85)
      1072: "Human Depravity."
    - Nos. {1074, [no number]}, 1830, 1850 (Box 11, Folder 86)